Christensen, C. Roland (Carl Roland), 1919-1999. C. Roland Christensen Papers, 1931-1998: A Finding Aid
C. Roland Christensen papers, 1931-1998
- II. HBS Teaching Records, 1931-1998
  - Subseries B. Business Policy Teaching Files, 1948-1990
    - Spiritual and Moral Values in Business, by Erwin Schell, BP 536 (Box 47, f. 3)
    - Stages of Corporate Development: a Descriptive Model, by Bruce Scott (Box 47, f. 4)
    - Stanton, J. & W., Ltd. (A) (B), GM 102-GM 103 (Box 47, f. 5)
    - Studebaker Corporation, BP 482 (Box 47, f. 6)
    - Tennessee Coal and Iron (A), BP 783 (Box 47, f. 7)
    - Texas Instruments, Inc. (A), condensed, BP 901 (Box 47, f. 8)
    - Theological Bases of Social Action, by J.L. Adams (Box 47, f. 9)
    - Theological Conception of Goals for Economic Life, by J.C. Bennett, BP 538 (Box 47, f. 10)
    - Theory of Advice, Notes on, by Lymon Bryson (Box 47, f. 11)
    - Thoughts about Thought in High Places, by Dean Acheson, BP 667 (Box 47, f. 12)
    - Tire Industry, Note on, BP 850 (Box 47, f. 13)
    - Tire Industry, Note on the United States, BP 890 (Box 47, f. 14)
    - Typewriter Industry, Note on What Used to be the (B), BP 690 (Box 47, f. 15)
    - Uniroyal, Inc., BP 892 (Box 47, f. 16)
    - United Industries (R), BP 748 (Box 47, f. 17)
    - U.S. Time Corporation, BP 931, IMEDE, GM 182 (Box 47, f. 18)
    - United Wall Paper Factories, PBA 12 (Box 47, f. 19)
    - Univis, Inc., AMP 250 (Box 47, f. 20)
    - Variable Annuities, by C.M. Shanks (Box 47, f. 21)
    - Vinyl Plastisols, Technical Note on the Manufacture of, BP 737 (Box 47, f. 22)
    - Wayland Co., BP 571 (Box 47, f. 23)
    - The West Debates the Great Growth Issue, BP 772 (Box 47, f. 24)
    - White Motor Corporation, BP 861 (Box 47, f. 25)
    - Wilson, Roger, BP 878 (Box 47, f. 26)
    - World Wrist Watch Industry, Note on, BP 648r (Box 47, f. 27)
    - Xerox Corporation, BP 838 (Box 47, f. 28)
  - Subseries C. Case Development Files, Nike, Inc., 1983-1984
    This subseries consists of folders created by Christensen while developing teaching cases concerning Nike in 1984. Materials include handwritten notes and questions, as well as a transcript of his 1983 interview with Nike's co-founder Philip Knight.
    - Nike, notes, etc. (Box 48, f. 1)
    - Nike (A), 0-385-025 (Box 48, f. 2)
    - Nike (A), 0-385-025 (Box 48, f. 3)
    - Nike (A), 5-385-092 (Box 48, f. 4)
    - Nike (A1), 0-385-026 (Box 48, f. 5)
    - Nike (B), 0-385-027 (Box 48, f. 6)
    - Nike (B1), 0-385-028 (Box 48, f. 7)
    - Nike (C), 0-385-029 (Box 48, f. 8)
    - Nike (C1), 0-385-030 (Box 48, f. 9)
    - Nike (C2), draft (Box 48, f. 10)
    - Nike (D), 0-385-031 (Box 48, f. 11)
    - Nike (D1), 0-385-032 (Box 48, f. 12)
    - Nike (E)(E1)(E2)(E3)(E4)(E5), 0-385-033 - 0385-038 (Box 48, f. 13)
    - Nike (F)(F1), 0-385-039 and 0-385-040 (Box 49, f. 1)
    - Nike: International Context, 0-385-328 (Box 49, f. 2)
    - Transcript Interview, Philip Knight, from tape made at Nike, Inc., 1983 (Box 49, f. 3)
  - Subseries D. Colloquium on Teaching by the Case Method, 1984-1988
    This subseries consists of files relating to the HBS Colloquium on Teaching by the Case Method held in 1984 in honor of the school's seventy-fifth anniversary. Materials include schedules, background readings and speeches. Of special interest is a speech by HBS student Robin Hacke, describing from a student perspective how the case method affects business education.
    - Program Schedule and Organization, 1984 (Box 49, f. 4-6)
    - Directory of Participants, April 1-4, 1984 (Box 49, f. 7)
    - Publicity, 1984-1988 (Box 49, f. 8)
    - Speech material, 1984 (Box 49, f. 9)
    - Speeches, general, 1984 (Box 49, f. 10-12)
    - Speeches: Hacke, Robin, “The Case Method, a Student Perspective,” 1984 (Box 50, f. 1)
    - Speeches: Schon, Donald, 1984 (Box 50, f. 2)
  - Subseries E. Field Studies, 1964-1984
    This subseries reflects the activities of HBS students conducting field studies at business locations throughout the United States. Files include instructions for interviewing in the field, notes on observation techniques, course materials for Field Studies and Business Policy classes, and sample readings.
    - Business Policy Field Studies, 1974-1983 (Box 50, f. 3)
    - Business Policy Field Study Teams, 1978 (Box 50, f. 4)
    - Business Policy, Field Studies, 1981-1983 (Box 54, f. 5)
    - Clinical Research Seminar, Observing, 1964 (Box 50, f. 6-7)
    - Exhibits, Field Study, undated (Box 50, f. 8)
    - Field Research, Business Policy, 1978 (Box 50, f. 9)
    - Field Studies, Business Policy, 1980-1982 (Box 50, f. 10)
    - Field Studies in Business Policy, 1981 (Box 50, f. 11)
    - Field Studies in Business Policy, A Suggested Basic Library in Management, January 1981 (Box 50, f. 12)
    - Field Studies, Business Policy, 1982 (Box 50, f. 13)
    - Field Studies, correspondence, 1982 (Box 50, f. 14)
    - Field Studies in Business Policy, excerpts from a typical course outline, ca. 1981 (Box 51, f. 1)
    - Field Studies in Business Policy, overview, n.d. (Box 51, f. 2)
    - Field Studies Program, 1982-1983 (Box 51, f. 3)
    - Field Studies, sample readings, n.d. (Box 51, f. 4)
    - “The Field Study Is for You!” 1981 (Box 51, f. 5)
    - “How a Field Study Is Done,” n.d. (Box 51, f. 6)
    - “How To Blow It,” undated, 9-380-203 (Box 51, f. 7)
    - Instructions to Interviewers, HP 115 (Box 51, f. 8)
    - Observation exercise, undated (Box 51, f. 9)
    - Opening questions, policy class, 1978 (Box 51, f. 10)
    - “Remembrances of a Field Study,” 1984 (Box 51, f. 11)
    - Strategic Prediction, 1974 (Box 51, f. 12)
  - Subseries F. Teaching Materials and Course Development, 1947-1996
    This subseries consists of material related to teaching and course development, and includes course outlines, reading lists, handwritten notes, transcripts of presentations, memoranda, seating charts and rosters from HBS courses. Among the courses represented are Administrative Policy (1947-1953), Business Policy (1951-1979), Developing Discussion Leadership Skills (1978-1983), and Faculty Teaching Seminars (1982-1986). Developing Discussion Leadership Skills and Faculty Teaching Seminars were designed to sharpen the classroom skills of instructors who employ discussion teaching or the case method.
    Course-specific materials are followed by general materials arranged in chronological order.
    - Administrative Policy, Notes on First Class, 1947-1954 (Box 51, f. 13)
    - Administrative Policy I and II, Outlines and Notices, 1948-1949 (Box 51, f. 14)
    - Administrative Policy I and II, Outlines and Notices, 1949-1950 (Box 51, f. 15)
    - Administrative Policy I, Outlines and Notices, 1950-1951 (Box 51, f. 16)
    - Administrative Policy I, Report Class, October 1950 (Box 51, f. 17)
    - Administrative Policy II, Outlines and Notices, 1951 (Box 51, f. 18)
    - Administrative Policy I, Outlines and Notices, 1952-1953 (Box 51, f. 19)
    - Business Policy, Planning, 1951-1952 (Box 51, f. 20)
    - Business Policy I, September 1951 (Box 51, f. 21)
    - Business Policy, Student Report Class, 1951-1953 (Box 51, f. 22)
    - Business Policy, Planning, 1952-1953 (Box 51, f. 23)
    - Business Policy II, February 1952 (Box 51, f. 24)
    - Business Policy I Material "B", Fall 1953 (Box 51, f. 25)
    - Business Policy I Material "D", Fall 1953 (Box 51, f. 26)
    - Business Policy I, Notes/Outlines, 1953-1954 (Box 51, f. 27)
    - Business Policy, 1953-1954 (Box 52, f. 1)
    - Business Policy II, Sample Final Reports, Spring 1954 (Box 52, f. 2)
    - Business Policy II, Section C, Spring 1954 (Box 52, f. 3)
    - Business Policy, 1957-1958 (Box 52, f. 4)
    - Business Policy, Summary Notes, 1957-1958 (Box 52, f. 5)
    - Business Policy, Class Summary, November 1, 1957 (Box 52, f. 6)
    - Business Policy II, 1957-1958 (Box 52, f. 7)
    - Business Policy, Spring 1958 (Box 52, f. 8)
    - Business Policy II, Spring 1958 (Box 52, f. 9)
    - Business Policy, Final Speech, June 1958 (Box 52, f. 10)
    - Business Policy, 1958-1961 (Box 52, f. 11)
    - Business Policy, Summary, February 24, 1959 (Box 52, f. 12)
    - Business Policy, Summary Comments, May 12, 1959 (Box 52, f. 13)
    - Business Policy, Introductory Comments, September 21, 1959 (Box 52, f. 14)
    - Business Policy, Summary Speech, December 1959 (Box 52, f. 15)
    - Business Policy I, Summary Course Comments, December 1959 (Box 52, f. 16)
    - Business Policy, 1959-1960 (Box 52, f. 17)
    - Business Policy, Summary, April 1960 (Box 52, f. 18)
    - Business Policy, Summary Comments, May 17, 1960 (Box 52, f. 19)
    - Business Policy, First Class Session, September 1960 (Box 52, f. 20)
    - Business Policy II, Summary Course Comments, May 17, 1963 (Box 53, f. 1-2)
    - Business Policy Symposium, Spring 1963 (Box 53, f. 3)
    - Business Policy, Summaries/Speeches/Comments, 1963-1988 (Box 53, f. 4)
    - Business Policy, Planning, 1964-1965 (Box 53, f. 5)
    - Business Policy II, Section I, 1964-1965 (Box 53, f. 6)
    - Business Policy, Spring Term, 1964-1965 (Box 53, f. 7)
    - Business Policy, Summary Session, October 1965 (Box 53, f. 8)
    - Business Policy, Course Planning, 1965-1966 (Box 53, f. 9)
    - Business Policy, March 1966 (Box 53, f. 10)
    - Business Policy, Final Speech, May 1967 (Box 53, f. 11)
    - Business Policy, Course Information, Spring 1967 (Box 53, f. 12)
    - Business Policy, Summary, November 1967 (Box 53, f. 13)
    - Business Policy II, Course Material, Spring 1968 (Box 53, f. 14)
    - Business Policy, Course Plans, Spring 1969 (Box 53, f. 15)
    - Business Policy II, Section A, Spring 1969 (Box 53, f. 16)
    - Business Policy, Final Lecture, December 19, 1969 (Box 53, f. 17)
    - Business Policy I, Fall 1970 (Box 53, f. 1)
    - Business Policy II, Section A, Spring 1971 (Box 54, f. 2)
    - Business Policy, Student Information Cards (blank), 1973 (Box 53, f. 3)
    - Business Policy Teaching Seminar, Public Evaluation, 1974-1975 (Box 54, f. 4)
    - Business Policy Doctoral Teaching Seminar, 1975 (Box 54, f. 5)
    - Business Policy Doctoral Teaching Seminar, 1977 (Box 54, f. 6)
    - Business Policy (as taught at MIT), 1977 (Box 54, f. 7)
    - Business Policy (as taught at Harvard Law School), 1979 (Box 54, f. 8)
    - Central American Series, Teaching Plan, 1966 (Box 54, f. 9)
    - Developing Discussion Leadership Skills Seminar, 1983 (Box 54, f. 10)
    - Developing Discussion Teaching Skills Seminar, 1978-1980 (Box 54, f. 11-12)
    - Faculty Teaching Seminar, 1982 (Box 54, f. 13)
    - Faculty Teaching Seminar, "When the Business School Professor is a Woman", Faculty Teaching Seminar Materials by Abby Hansen, 1983 (Box 54, f. 14)
    - Faculty Teaching Seminar, 1984 (Box 54, f. 15)
    - Faculty Teaching Seminar, 1986 (Box 54, f. 16)
    - IMEDE, Introductory Session, January 9, 1964 (Box 55, f. 1)
    - IMEDE, Summary, May 21, 1964 (Box 55, f. 2)
    - Management Session in Small and Growing Enterprises, Seminar on Organizational Analysis, April 20, 1960 (Box 55, f. 3)
    - "The Dashman Company" Teaching Materials, circa 1947-1998 (Box 55, f. 4)
    - Harvard Business School Bulletin, "The First Fifty Years", August 1958 (Box 55, f. 5)
    - "Planning for Change: Report of the MBA Study Committee", September 1961 (Box 55, f. 6)
    - "Letter to a Business Policy Professor", May 3, 1973 (Box 55, f. 7)
    - Section Involvement Via Role Playing, 1975-1976 (Box 55, f. 8)
    - General Notes and Materials, 1976-1987 (Box 55, f. 9)
    - Orientation to Harvard Business School, Fall 1996 (Box 55, f. 10)
    - General Teaching Notes, undated (Box 55, f. 11)
    - Notes on the Early Class Session, undated (Box 55, f. 12)
  - Subseries G. Teaching About Teaching, 1931-1998
    The materials in this subseries consist primarily of teaching materials related to seminars, workshops, colloquia and other courses taught by Christensen. Main seminar topics are Developing Discussion Leadership Skills and Teaching by the Case Method. Included are annotated cases, topical notes, correspondence, permission requests and agreements, teaching plans, questions, notes, agendas, memoranda, quotations, newspaper and other periodical clippings, seminar schedules and programs, and catalogs of seminar participants. Also present are files containing Christensen's thoughts and reflections on teaching, including handwritten notes, clippings and cartoons. This subseries also contains digital content of Teaching and the Case Method and of work relating to teaching and class discussion. This subseries consists of four subgroups.
    These records were added to the collection in 2007.
    - i. Annotated Cases Used for Teaching About Teaching, circa 1940-1998
      This subgroup consists primarily of cases developed by Christensen, Dr. Abby J. Hansen and others for use in Developing Discussion Leadership Skills and Teaching by the Case Method seminars. Teaching notes and supplementary materials are included.
      Cases are arranged alphabetically.
      - "Am I Going to Have to Do This by Myself?:" Diversity and the Discussion Teacher (B), Graduate School of Education, 1992 (Box 55, f. 13)
      - Assistant Professor Graham and Ms. Macomber (B), 1978-1995 (Box 55, f. 14-16)
      - Assistant Professor Graham and Ms. Macomber, 1994-1998 (Box 55, f. 17)
      - B & C Cases, 1982-1984 (Box 55, f. 18)
      - Bill Jones, circa 1995 (Box 55, f. 19-21)
      - Bill Jones, circa 1995 (Box 56, f. 1)
      - The Blank Page, 1996 (Box 56, f. 2)
      - The Blooper of the Week, 1987-1998 (Box 56, f. 3-5)
      - Bob Lunt, 1982 (Box 56, f. 6)
      - Bob Thompson, 1978-1981 (Box 56, f. 7)
      - Bound Feet, circa 1990-1991 (Box 56, f. 8-10)
      - The Case of the Derailed Discussion, circa 1998 (Box 56, f. 11-13)
      - Cases (disbound volume), 1976-1990 (Box 56, f. 14-15)
      - Cases (disbound volume), 1976-1990 (Box 57, f. 1-2)
      - Cases (disbound volume), loose papers, circa 1997 (Box 57, f. 3)
      - Charles Sexton, 1986 (Box 57, f. 4)
      - Class on World Hunger, circa 1987-1990 (Box 57, f. 5-6)
      - The Day the Heat Went On, 1983-1993 (Box 57, f. 7)
      - The Dethroned Section Leader, 1985-1997 (Box 57, f. 8-11)
      - Ernie Budding, 1980-1995 (Box 57, f. 12-14)
      - The Etiology of Childhood, 1987 (Box 58, f. 1)
      - The Final Exam, 1996 (Box 58, f. 2)
      - The French Lesson, 1988-1996 (Box 58, f. 3-4)
      - George Perkins, 1986-1995 (Box 58, f. 5-6)
      - The Handicapped Heckler, 1985-1995 (Box 58, f. 7-9)
      - The Handicapped Heckler, undated (Box 58, f. 10)
      - HBS Cases (disbound volume), 1975-1990 (Box 58, f. 11-13)
      - HBS Cases (disbound volume), 1975-1990 (Box 59, f. 1-2)
      - HBS Cases: Teaching Notes and Readings (disbound volume), circa 1940-1988 (Box 59, f. 3-9)
      - Herr Faber's New Course (A), Harvard Graduate School of Education, 1991 (Box 59, f. 10)
      - How Do You Expect Us to Get This if It Isn't in Your Notes?, Harvard School of Public Health, 1992 (Box 59, f. 11)
      - I Felt as if My World Had Just Collapsed!, circa 1990 (Box 59, f. 12)
      - If This Hadn't Happened, None of Us Would Have Remembered Him, circa 1991 (Box 59, f. 13)
      - The Introduction, circa 1988-1993 (Box 59, f. 14)
      - The Introduction, circa 1988-1993 (Box 60, f. 1)
      - Kurt Jacobs, circa 1981-1987 (Box 60, f. 2-3)
      - Message Intended and Message Received, 1990 (Box 60, f. 4)
      - Nike, 1984 (Box 60, f. 5)
      - Nike, Teaching Notes, 1984 (Box 60, f. 6-7)
      - The Offended Colonel (A and B), 1983-1996 (Box 60, f. 8-10)
      - Peter Morgan, 1988-1993 (Box 60, f. 11)
      - The Puzzling Student, 1989-1994 (Box 60, f. 12-13)
      - The Puzzling Student, 1989-1994 (Box 61, f. 1-2)
      - A Question of Cookies, 1992 (Box 61, f. 3)
      - The Section Just Took Over: A Student's Reflections, 1980-1996 (Box 61, f. 4-5)
      - The Section Was Mine to Lose, 1981-1988 (Box 61, f. 6-8)
      - Suzie Simons, 1977-1982 (Box 61, f. 9)
      - That Discussion Just Fell Apart, 1982 (Box 61, f. 10)
      - The Thin Grey Line, 1987-1994 (Box 61, f. 11-12)
      - Trevor Jones, 1981-1995 (Box 62, f. 1-2)
      - Trouble in Stat. 1B, Graduate School of Education, circa 1992 (Box 62, f. 3)
      - When the Cat's Away, Harvard School of Public Health, 1994 (Box 62, f. 4)
      - Who Should Teach?, 1987-1994 (Box 62, f. 5-6)
      - Winter Oak, 1992-1997 (Box 62, f. 7-8)
    - ii. Reflections, 1975-1997
      The records included in this subgroup consist of Christensen's personal notes, topical notes, reflections on teaching and on life in general, as well as articles, periodical clippings, cartoons, and quotations culled by Christensen. They provide interesting insight into his personal philosophy and thoughts on teaching.
      - Fun, 1986-1996 (Box 62, f. 9)
      - Fun, 1987-1993 (Box 62, f. 10)
      - Fun, 1995-1996 (Box 62, f. 11)
      - Humor, Sparkle, 1986-1995 (Box 62, f. 12)
      - Humor, n.d. (Box 62, f. 13)
      - Reflections, 1975-1986 (Box 62, f. 14)
      - Reflections, 1975-1986 (Box 63, f. 1)
      - Reflections, 1976-1993 (Box 63, f. 2)
      - Reflections/Clippings, circa 1980s (Box 63, f. 3-5)
      - Reflections, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 63, f. 6)
      - Reflections, 1990-1995 (Box 63, f. 7-8)
      - Reflections, Credo, circa 1992 (Box 63, f. 9)
      - Reflections, 1992-1997 (Box 63, f. 10)
      - Reflections, 1992-1997 (Box 64, f. 1)
      - Reflections, circa 1993-1997 (Box 64, f. 2)
      - Reflections, circa 1990s (Box 64, f. 3)
    - iii. Seminar Teaching Materials, circa 1950s-1997
      This subgroup consists of seminar-specific teaching notes, readings, correspondence, seminar outlines, seminar planning and other materials from Christensen's seminars, including Developing Discussion Leadership Skills, Teaching by the Case Method, Teaching and the Case Method, and others.
      Seminar materials are arranged chronologically.
      - Supplementary Cases and Readings - Teaching by the Case Method (disbound volume), circa 1950s-1990s (Box 64, f. 4)
      - Teaching Seminar Notes, 1965-1986 (Box 64, f. 5-6)
      - International Teachers Programme, London, July 1977 (Box 64, f. 7-8)
      - Introduction, Discussion Leadership Teaching Seminar, September 1977 (Box 64, f. 9)
      - Responses, 1978-1982 (Box 64, f. 10)
      - Sloan, Final Session, 1979 (Box 64, f. 11)
      - Colloquium on Teaching By the Case Method, April 1-4, 1984 (Box 64, f. 12)
      - Colloquium on Teaching By the Case Method draft material, undated; 001347577_FD_0023, 0040
        Digital use copies can be accessed only onsite in the de Gaspé Beaubien Reading Room. To request access please contact histcollref@hbs.edu prior to visiting the library.
      - Case Writing Workshop, July 23-24, 1984 (Box 65, f. 1)
      - Harvard Education School, Prior Summaries (Notes on Discussion Teaching), 1986-1991 (Box 65, f. 2)
      - Seminar Planning (Miscellaneous), 1987-1997 (Box 65, f. 3)
      - HBS Publishing Seminar #1, 1987-1997 (Box 65, f. 4)
      - Fordham University Teaching Seminar, 1988 (Box 65, f. 5)
      - Teaching By the Case Method, 1988-1990 (Box 65, f. 6)
      - Introductory and Concluding Comments, IBM, 1989-1991 (Box 65, f. 7)
      - Publishing Division, HBS, circa 1980s-1990s (Box 65, f. 8)
      - Seminar Planning, Extra Copies of Cases, circa 1980-1990s (Box 65, f. 9)
      - Summary, Harvard School of Education, Developing Discussion Leadership Skills, Fall 1990 (Box 65, f. 10)
      - Introduction, IBM Faculty Seminar on "Teaching and the Case Method", December 1991 (Box 65, f. 11)
      - Tufts, Teaching Workshop, 1991-1992 (Box 65, f. 12)
      - Introduction, Developing Discussion Leadership Skills, Harvard School of Public Health, 1991-1992 (Box 65, f. 13)
      - Summary, Harvard School of Education, 1992 (Box 65, f. 14)
      - Summary, Discussion Teaching, 1992-1996 (Box 65, f. 15)
      - Writings from Developing Discussion Leadership Skills Seminar, 1992-1996 (Box 65, f. 16)
      - The University of Utah, Developing Discussion Leadership Skills, February 25-27, 1993 (Box 65, f. 17)
      - The University of Utah, Developing Discussion Leadership Skills, March 3-November 4, 1993 (Box 65, f. 18)
      - The University of Utah, Developing Discussion Leadership Skills, April 29-May 1, 1993 (Box 65, f. 19)
      - Tufts Teaching Seminar, Fall 1993 (Box 66, f. 1)
      - Introduction, The University of Utah, Developing Discussion Leadership Skills, 1993 (Box 66, f. 2)
      - Summary, Tufts Teaching Seminar, 1993 (Box 66, f. 3)
      - Summary, Harvard School of Public Health, March 1994 (Box 66, f. 4)
      - Colloquium on Teaching by the Case Method, April 1-4, 1984 (Box 66, f. 5)
      - Harvard School of Public Health Faculty Seminar, Directory of Participants, Spring 1994 (Box 66, f. 6)
      - Harvard School of Public Health, Developing Discussion Leadership Skills, 1994 (Box 66, f. 7)
      - Summary, Harvard School of Education, December 1994 (Box 66, f. 8)
      - Pediatric Faculty Development, Harvard Medical School, 1994 (Box 66, f. 9)
      - The University of Utah, Background Information, 1994 (Box 66, f. 10-11)
      - Summary, Harvard School of Education, March 1995 (Box 66, f. 12)
      - H.E.C. University of Montreal, May 26, 1995 (Box 66, f. 13-14)
      - Harvard School of Education, Developing Discussion Leadership Skills, Spring 1995 (Box 66, f. 15-16)
      - International Teachers Programme, London, Background, 1995-1997 (Box 66, f. 17)
      - Programs, Developing Discussion Leadership Skills, 1995-1997 (Box 66, f. 18)
      - Seminar Planning, Developing Discussion Leadership Skills, January 17-March 20, 1996 (Box 67, f. 1)
      - HBS Doctoral Case Method Teaching Seminar, February 1996 (Box 67, f. 2)
      - Introduction/Comments, The University of Utah, Developing Discussion Leadership Skills, April 5-6 1996 (Box 67, f. 3)
      - The University of Utah, Developing Discussion Leadership Skills, April 5-6, 1996 (Box 67, f. 4)
      - Harvard Macy Institute, June 1996 (Box 67, f. 5)
      - Summary, The University of Utah, Second Developing Discussion Leadership Skills Seminar, 1996 (Box 67, f. 6)
      - The University of Utah, Seminar on Developing Discussion Leadership Skills, 1996 (Box 67, f. 7)
      - Summary, The University of Utah, David Eccles School of Business, circa 1996 (Box 67, f. 8)
      - Observation and Overview, Carlson School of Management Opening Session, Developing Discussion Leadership Skills, February 1997 (Box 67, f. 9)
      - Carlson School of Management, Developing Discussion Leadership Skills, February 1997 (Box 67, f. 10)
      - The Art and Craft of Discussion Leadership - A Seminar on the Case Method, April 4-5, 1997 (Box 67, f. 11)
      - Introduction, Harvard Macy Institute, June 1997 (Box 67, f. 12)
      - The Art and Craft of Discussions Leadership, HBS Publishing, November 7-8, 1997 (Box 67, f. 13-14)
      - Carlson School of Management, Developing Discussion Leadership Skills (Administrative), 1997 (Box 67, f. 15)
    - iv. General, 1931-1998
      This subgroup includes teaching materials and readings, teaching and topical notes, materials on Christensen's books Teaching and the Case Method and Education for Judgment: The Artistry of Discussion Leadership, publications not authored by Christensen and other materials. This subseries also contains digital content of Teaching and the Case Method and of work relating to teaching and class discussion.
      The records are arranged chronologically.
      - "Teaching and the Case Method", 4th Ed., 1931-1995 (Box 67, f. 16-18)
      - "Teaching and the Case Method", 4th Ed., 1931-1996 (Box 68, f. 1)